The world is still unsure about how this
is going to play out. I'm not unsure.
I'm willing to bet it all.
>> What's up, Chris? Good to see you again.
>> Hey, Sean. How you doing, man?
>> I'm good. So, we should start with a
little a little intro. Sam, you weren't
here last time Chris was on. Chris, can
you do like the the the simplest
explanation of who you are? number one.
And then number two is your kind of
unique philosophy and unique strategy
that you've used to buy, you know, buy
and sell stocks to invest.
>> Yeah. I mean, I'm a reg I'm a regular
person for most of my career. I've had a
regular job. Uh I'm not a financial
analyst. I'm not a technical trader. I
hate all that stuff. I hate technicals.
I hate fundamentals. I'm like most
regular people, right? like a normal guy
with the normal job that was trying to
break out, you know, try to find a
future for myself because I realized
that my job was capped like 99.9% of
people in this world. And you know I
started investing something I call
observational investing or social
investing which is really all it is is
trying to detect change in the world
whether it's change in technological
development or change in culture change
in consumer behavior but you're trying
to detect change and you're trying to
connect that change uh connect the dots
to companies that would either benefit
or be harmed by that change. So you're
and then you're investing in those
companies. It's it's that simple.
>> One of many of ways that you personally
observe is through social media
comments.
>> Yeah. I mean like think about it like
how do you observe change in the world
the quickest? What do people do before
they change their life? They talk about
it, right? Before you can see the
evidence of it, they talk about it. If
you're a developer and and you're
changing the way that you develop
software and you're you're adopting AI
in your company, you're probably in
Reddit forums with other developers
speaking about it. [snorts]
>> And it's not always tech. A lot of it is
just consumer behavior, right? Because
uh I remember you had one that was
around the sphere, which most people
don't even realize. That's the big the
big dome in Vegas, the sphere.
>> It's a publicly traded stock. And I
think you noticed what was it the Wizard
of Oz. You you were like, "Dude, this
Wizard of Oz show."
>> Yeah. Game game game game changer,
right? They didn't quite nail product
market fit the sphere until that Wizard
of Oz came out and they're like, "Oh,
take an old movie, use AI to make it
more interesting in terms of visuals to
put it on this insane projection screen,
and then add some 4D effects like a
tornado and the winds blowing and all
this stuff." And all of a sudden, you
created a unique human experience that
would go viral on TikTok, which is
exactly what happened. And now people
from around the world from Europe are
like, "We're going to Vegas to go to
this spear place to see this Wizard of
Oz that we saw went viral on TikTok,
right?" And so, man, what a game
changer.
>> Did you buy it,
>> dude? Yeah.
>> So, I I heard him talking about it, so I
started tracking it. It's up 220% in the
last year.
>> I mean, from the time we got in, which
is like at 20 something bucks, it's up
like 6x or something. Chris, I got to
give you a little credit because anytime
somebody comes on the pod and talks
about investing, the goal is first to
get context on, okay, before we listen
and and really drink the Kool-Aid on all
the your philosophy or your strategy, we
like to understand does it work? What
what are the what are the results? And
so, you can talk a little bit about
that, but I'll give one little point,
which was last time you were on the pod,
I asked you to make three sort of picks,
three predictions, three three stocks to
look at. You said Palunteer, Bloom
Energy, it was at $92, is now at 240, so
it's up 165% since the last podcast. And
then Nvidia, which is up a smaller
amount, but those were your three picks.
So, I got to give give you a little bit
of credit.
>> So, here's the thing. Like, I actually
aggressively disagree with that type of
performance analysis because the world's
changing every minute of every day. So I
the day after the show I could have
found new information that would have
put me on the opposite side of all three
of those trades, right? And so the only
way you could ever analyze any investor
ever is through long-term audits over a
long period of time total portfolio. I
don't care if an investor comes on gives
you five stocks and all of them rocket.
It could have been based on beta, could
have been based on the like it
completely luck, right? Uh, so don't
give me any credit for anything from the
last show if you don't want. I mean, you
feel free if you want, but all that
actually matters is what's like the 10,
15, 20 year total portfolio track record
in and out through multiple markets.
>> Great. So, so what is it? What are the
audited? What is it? 15 year results.
>> It's like 68% over over 16 15 or 16
years.
>> What does that mean in terms of dollars?
What did you start with? I generated
about 80 million off of an initial
$20,000 portfolio that I kicked off in
2007.
>> Wow. And then do you reinvest new
capital into that?
>> The truth is that I took massive amounts
of capital out every year, almost all of
my profits. And so theoretically, if I
kept it all in and maintained the same
returns, which would have been harder
because the account would have been
larger obviously, it'd be like at 700
million or something like that. Um, but
you know, the truth is it's meaningfully
easier to manage an account that is 7 to
8 figures than an account that's nine
figures for obvious reasons, right? So
you can never really compare apples to
apples. You can't really compare me to a
guy managing 5 billion. It's unfair to
the guy that's managing 5 billion cuz he
has restrictions. He's having to move
large amounts of money. I'm able to be
hyper flexible with what I do. But I
would say that the sizing of my account
is still meaningfully larger than just
about any other retail investor in the
world.
>> What's been the worst downswing? What
year did you do the worst or what's
what's been the biggest dip you had?
>> I think I have it wasn't crazy. It was
like 30% down, 20 or 30% down in a year.
I think the biggest up years might have
been like 300% in a year. So, but it's
been relatively relatively consistent.
So, Chris, I want to ask you a question.
After you came on and you talked about
this observational investing and I have
to say I I obviously was I'm a bit
skeptical about most financial
influencers on YouTube. I would just say
like that's just a general stance I
have.
>> You should be more than skeptical.
[laughter]
>> Yeah. So, so uh but but you know when
you what you talked about is didn't it's
not like it was some uh insane idea like
you look for changes of where where you
see the world going where you think
demand is going where there might be
supply constraints and those obviously
might be interesting companies. Now the
question I have for you cuz one one
example is uh my kids went crazy about
these things called Neidos. Explain what
these things are. They're basically just
a pile of it's just like a goop ball. I
don't even what do you even explain it?
>> It's just it's just a squishy toy. It
it's a squishy toy that is slightly
firmer, slightly higher quality.
Squishies have been around for 15 years.
Uh but they were able to go viral this
last year. It became a thing in kind of
elementary and middle schools of like
finding rare Netos. You couldn't find
them. So they had that sort of like that
Pokemon card. This happens a lot of
times with crazes, right?
>> But is Neato a public company?
>> Yeah. So, so NATO is a very tiny private
company that's actually held by another
private company that owns I think 27
private companies. And NATO, the company
that owns NATO is one of those 27
companies. What's interesting is that
this is a holding company that jock that
generally doesn't move because they
generate their earnings from interest
payments and dividends paid by these
small operating companies. To my
knowledge, and the ticker is G A I N. To
my knowledge, they've never owned a
company that has had a hyper viral
product like Neato before. Can you
imagine that a Wolf of Wall Street call
to Sean like, "Listen, Sean, this is a
small company in Andover, Massachusetts
that is sitting on breakthrough
technology that is extra squishy yet
firm at the same time."
>> That's exactly what it is, man. That's
literally exactly what it is. And by the
way, whenever you invest in a tiny
company like this, there's all types of
unknown risk involved. Uh, so it's a
really dangerous game to play. But I did
make the investment. It's a bit of a
novelty investment and a novelty
product. So I the thesis is that if the
if neato can remain on trend through the
holiday season and if the parent company
is able to fully scale out supply,
this is actually going to be a needle
mover for the parent company to the and
and you should see about a 30 to 40%
increase in valuation at the parent
company.
>> Let's break this trade even further.
There's all these cool books on like uh
you know Warren Buffett's first like 50
deals or whatever. Let's do uh Chris's
uh investment into Neiditos. Could you
say how much did you put into it? When
did you put into it? And like when
you're saying there should be a 30 or
40%, what numbers did you look at to
make this estimation of what how much
juice is on here or how how much profit
it can could be had.
>> You're basically looking at
>> Hey, let's take a quick break because
the team at HubSpot has put together
something pretty cool. You know, in this
episode, Chris is talking about the way
he knows how to make money. Identifying
these trends, scouting the Tik Tok
comments, making these big leveraged
bets. That's great for him. It is
amazing. Some people will like that. I
personally don't know how to make money
that way. I wouldn't do it. But I've
talked before about the way that I know
how to make money, about how to build a
money-making skill, about how to
leverage your time and energy. And the
team at HubSpot actually went through
the video where I explained all that and
turned it into a free downloadable cheat
sheet on my four rules of how to make
money. Now, this is not, you know, get
rich quick advice. It's just core
principles, foundational principles
about building wealth, things that I
wish I knew when I was, you know, just
getting started. And so, if you want to
download it, it's in the description
below. It's totally free. You can go get
it. Thanks to the folks at HubSpot for
doing the research, making this
document, and making it available to all
you guys. All right, back to this
episode.
>> You're basically looking at how many
Neidos you think the company can sell
through the holiday season based on
demand and how many they're currently
selling. By the way, this is like a
little bit of a science and a little bit
of an art and and you kind of assess
what that will do to that company's
bottom line. How that will increase
dividends and what that increased
dividend payment to the parent company
will account for relative to the total
valuation of the parent company. It it's
it's it's kind of a difficult exercise
and this is where AI comes in really
great because AI can help you do that
exercise. So we're, you know, we're not
financial analysts and AI does an
excellent job going deep into the
financials of a company like this and
then like okay, if they sell this many
at this much of a profit margin, it
could have this big of an impact on the
parent company and of earnings come the
holiday season. So again, lot lot of
estimates that you're making. It was
enough for me to invest. I put like
somewhere between half a million and a
half and a million dollars into the
trade. It wasn't crazy. I did it more
because I love the product and I love
the trade and I felt the trade's going
to work and I wanted to be part of it.
So like for me on an equity trade,
that's not a huge trade for me, but I
like it. And and by the way, if you look
at the past 17 years, I've made about 80
to 85 high conviction trades over 17
years. So the entirety of my performance
is based on those 80 trades.
>> And Neato was a high conviction.
>> I wouldn't call Neato a high conviction.
I call probably a medium conviction
because the company's so tiny
that there are a lot of variables
that could impact a minuscule company
like that. But um all 80 of those trades
were publicly discussed more or less as
they were happening. So, I'm really
public with my ideas because I I want my
community to kind of provide feedback
and poke holes in my thesis. You know,
there aren't that many of us social arb
traders, observational traders. So, I've
always said that the community at large
when we work together on ideas.
Sometimes I surface ideas, sometimes
members of my community surface ideas,
we cross research them. We we play
devil's advocate with each other. We
poke holes in the thesis. And I always
say as as a group, we're more powerful
than the biggest hedge fund because we
have, you know, tens to hundreds of
thousands of people now that are social
arbit traders and we come from every
walk of life. So we have people from
every industry sector, every profession,
every demographic. So we have tons of
people that have kids. When we do
channel checks, when we do store checks,
I'll throw it out in my community and
they will they will do store checks in
every state. So, we'll have people
aggregating. Hey, I went to this shop in
Missouri. I went to this shop in
Florida. Here's what the clerk told me.
Right. It it's really really fun, guys.
>> Now, let me ask you a question about
this. The specific question I have is
observing the trend if especially if
you're a parent with with young kids, it
was actually not that hard. It was
pretty easy to see, holy [\h__\h] every kid
in the school wants it and there's none
on the shelves. Uh they can't, you know,
stores can't keep them in stock. People
are banging out the door. So, the buy
side of that kind of makes some sense to
me. But all these things seem like fads.
They seem like trends. I would never
know when to exit a trade like this. I
would I never know when to sell because
I I don't think 20 years from now my
kids are going to care about NATO or the
kids are necessarily going to care about
NATO. So, can you explain how you think
about the the exit or the sell when it's
come when it's something like this where
it's like a trend or a a wave that may
not be enduring?
>> Well, well, let let's back up. It all it
all is dependent upon the conviction
level and the underlying thesis
that you observed, right? So you you
have a thesis that you come up with that
there is some new information that is
likely to positively or impact this
company or this sector that the market
is not aware of yet or that the market
underappreciates.
Now you have to ask yourself to what
extent is this a needle mover for this
company, right? Is this going to
meaningfully move the revenue needle,
the profit needle, their cost structure
or the perception of this company? Is it
meaningful? And are there other things
that are happening to this company that
are more meaningful than this one piece
of information that I feel is a needle
mover? Okay. And then you have to ask
yourself to what extent do other
investors institutional or retail
already know about this because it's not
a binary thing right some people might
know but does the market at large fully
appreciate that piece of information or
do they only partially appreciate it so
it's additive and you have to determine
am I highly convicted in this trade
because this thing that's about to
happen or that already happened is going
be massively impactful to this company.
And there's nothing else that's going to
impact this company over the course of
the next few weeks or the next couple of
months. And there are virtually no other
investors in institutional or retail
that understand this yet. And to answer
your question, Sean, the exit window is
when other people come to terms with
this information, right? When other
people start to appreciate this
information that you found that you
traded on, as soon as that information
becomes public, like in the case of the
sphere, when other retail traders, when
financial press, when the company itself
and analysts started coming out with
reports saying, "Hey, they're selling
out the arena due to Wizard of Oz. This
is going to be a gamecher. We're
starting to revise our earnings
estimates based on this new template
that they found with the Wizard of Oz.
And by the way, they can replicate this
model now with other old movies and it's
a highly profitable model. And we now
feel that they've kind of cracked
product market fit at Sphere, which is a
game-changing moment. When you start to
hear about that in the press, when you
see other investors talking about it on
X, when the company itself talks about
it, that's the point of information
parody and that's when we exit the
trade. So you basically initiate an
observational social orb trade at the
point of information imbalance when you
find some information that is impactful
that the world doesn't know about yet
and you exit that investment as the
world starts to appreciate that
information. And that's not always a
binary event either. Sometimes you exit
it over time as more and more investors
start to appreciate the information. Now
you try to ignore stock price. The
assumption is that if that piece of
information is meaningfully positive to
that company as other people start to to
to to surface that information that it
will positively impact the stock, but
that's out of your control. The bottom
line is you're trading a thesis. Your
thesis revolves around one piece of
information. And when that information
gets widely disseminated to other
investors, then you no longer have an
information advantage. Therefore, you
should be exiting that trade. Whether
you made money in the trade or whether
you lost money in the trade for some
other unknown reason, maybe the market,
maybe something else happened is kind of
irrelevant. So that's the entire
methodology. That's everything I've been
doing for 17 years. there's a lot more
to it because like when you find this
narrative, right? You then need to like
check every other piece of information
that you can or data source to validate
it. Talking to store clerks, right?
Maybe you're pulling web traffic stats.
Maybe you're looking at Google search
trends. Depending on the trade, there's
a million different ways to validate the
narrative thesis that you originated
using alternative data or other
information sources.
It just it's a case-bycase basis, but
this is everything I've been doing for
17 years. And it's very different from
being a fundamental trader or being a
technical trader.
>> Has there been a time over the last 15
or 18 years that you've been doing this
where you've said I'm quitting and I'm
uh I'm not doing this anymore. I'm going
back to like just index investing or
something like has what what was the low
point?
>> No, I love this so much, guys. This is
literally part of my soul. This is what
I do. I I have so much fun doing this.
Like, you got to realize like my
methodology entails reading comments on
Tik Tok videos. I get to watch the world
unfold. I get to learn about culture and
consumer behavior and trends and what
people are buying, what they're doing.
It is the funnest research any investor
could ever do. I'm not studying
fundamentals or charts. What I do is fun
as hell. I then every five years I have
this thesis that I go all in on. So five
years ago it was Pokemon and nerd
culture and I started this company
called Collecticon and we became the
largest Pokemon trade show in the world
and we sold it to Ari Emanuel a few
months ago for an insane amount of money
but we grew that from the ground up and
I kind of take on one of those projects.
the next project I'm taking on.
>> Wait, can we tell me about this? That's
that's a big deal.
>> Tell tell the full story before you tell
the new new product.
>> Oh, you want to know the story? This is
actually amazing. I always tell
everyone,
don't do things for yourself. Just go
out there and do things for other people
and it always comes back in your favor.
Don't ask how or why. It just generally
always does. So, I'm really big into
philanthropy. I have a 501 foundation.
and I support pediatric charity, animal
welfare and elder care. And back during
the pandemic, I know nothing about
Pokemon, okay? But Logan Paul bought
like a $350,000 Pokemon box, which is
the set the world record. And I was
like, man, that looks really fun. And I
was kind of bored. I'm gonna go do the
same thing, but then I'm gonna break it
into like the 24 packs and auction it
off for charity and then just donate it
all to the foundation. And I'm going to
also throw the world's biggest Pokemon
party in Vegas cuz I ended up meeting
all these Pokemon people and they were
the coolest, nicest people in the world.
I'm telling you, I never met people so
fun. And so I met Steve Aoki who's a big
Pokemon guy. I met this guy, Gary King
Pokemon, who's the number one Pokemon
guy collector in the world. And he was
the guy that I think sold Logan one of
his biggest Pokemon cards. And I said, I
want to do this party, guys. And they
helped me put on this party in Vegas.
And we agreed that a third of the
proceeds would go to Steve Aoki's brain
charity charities, like whatever. A
third would go to Gary King Pokemon's
autism charities, and a third would go
to the charities I care about. So, I
bought this box for $375,000.
We broke it up through the world's
biggest Pokemon party, [sighs] donated
hundreds and hundreds of thousands of
dollars to charity. The party itself
cost me almost $150,000
to put on. I made zero. All this was a
massive loss and donation to a bunch of
charities. But what came out of it, I
met all these really interesting people.
And about a month later, Gary King
Pokemon calls me. He goes, "Hey, Chris,
I know you believe in Pokemon now. I
know you believe that this is going to
be really big and get bigger every year.
One of the guys at the party wants to
start a Pokemon convention and he
doesn't have any money. Can I introduce
you? Maybe you would invest in it." I
said, "Yeah, sure. Let's do it." I had
lunch with this guy. He lived in Texas.
I said, "Let's just do it." This guy's
been working in in like conventions for
20 years. He had the perfect skill set
to do it. Him and his two cousins were
deeply passionate collectors and Pokemon
collectors. I said, "You guys are the
perfect people to run this conference.
Let's do it together." I invested
uh I want to say $600,000
into the company. I took a minority but
massive stake in the company and I
helped build this conference starting
with one show in a small hotel
convention room in Frisco, Texas.
And four years later, we were throwing
20 shows, 700,000 attendees,
the biggest Pokemon trade show in the
world, massive success. And by the way,
we all worked all the shows. Like I
would travel around the country and be
the guy who was ticketing people online
at 7 in the morning when we'd have 3,000
people in line because we were trying to
operate the show so efficiently cuz we
didn't have much huge business too. I
mean 700,000 tickets are
>> got to be a nine figure exit, right?
>> Massive business, guys. Massive. You
wouldn't believe I I'm under NDA. I
can't tell you the specifics of the
sale, but massive exit. Can can can you
say generally speaking these businesses
what do they sell for? Uh not yeah like
uh like on a ebida like what what's a
ebida multiple?
>> They don't sell for big multiples
because it's a it's a physical business.
It's not like a software business.
But the amount of money we were
generating from these shows was
enormous. It was really profitable. very
profitable because we care deeply about
the shows and we ran great shows. We
actually
>> I mean just doing back of the envelope
math 700,000 times let's say 60 bucks.
That's you're getting close to $50
million in revenue. Let alone vendors.
>> I can't disclose exact numbers but I'm
going to tell you the numbers were huge.
And we started from nothing and we built
this all up over 4 years. But it wasn't
easy guys. Like we we were so frugal
that we had our own rig because you know
the most expensive part of throwing a
convention is buying renting pipe and
drape at all the conventions. So we
bought our own pipe and drape put it in
a 18-wheeler and the founder operator of
this business Matthew would drive the
truck himself from city to city. It was
crazy. Okay. And and then we would
unload the truck with some local help,
right? And we would set up the shows or
so. I mean, there were points cuz I have
a bad back where after the first day I
was almost I couldn't walk and I there
were some shows I'd have to go home on
day two cuz I I I hurt my back so bad
from just like leaning over ticketing
thousands of people at the at the show
cuz we would hire contract workers to
help us but we needed every hand
possible.
>> That's pretty crazy.
>> And so we ran it like a family business.
We were deeply passionate about the
attendees. We would throw a concert
every Saturday midday. We had like
Vanilla Ice would perform or like it was
so fun. And and meanwhile to this day,
I've never bought a Pokemon card. So
like I was an observer of this scepter.
But the long story short, like I had
deep conviction
in nerd culture and Pokemon
specifically.
And I think Wall Street doesn't and just
business the business community
generally doesn't appreciate the fact
that there are millions of people that
like collecting these cards and no one
had provided a fun place for them to
physically go to once a year to connect
with other people like them and trade
these cards. Like we have sports card
shows, we've had them forever, right?
with baseball cards and whatnot, but no
one had ever really established a big
show for T, you know, TCG for like these
table card games, right? Like no one had
ever done it before. So, it just
intuitively made sense to me. So, so I'm
curious if this is something that others
have been doing or there's people you
look up to. So, for example, somebody
who you wouldn't think is an
observational trader, wouldn't call that
is Warren Buffett, but there's some
great stories of where he did exactly
what you're talking about. There's a a
story of the salad oil crisis with
American Express. I don't know if you
guys know that story, but it's
basically, you know, at a given time
they were lending money and they were
lending money to this guy who was
supposed to have salad oil dressing. And
then they went and they checked the
barrels and the barrels were just full
of water, salt water, like sea water.
And there was no salad oil at all. And
the stock is plummeting. And Buffett, he
figured out what the central question
was, which is, is this a temporary
setback or is this actually going to be
damaging to the trust of the brand long
term and he uh believed in brands,
right? That's why he has been on
Coca-Cola and Geico and these other
companies that he feels like have brands
that have power.
>> It's the exact opposite of what Chris
is. It's like what won't change.
>> Yeah. So he Well, he was but still the
the the market research part of this is
kind of shared, right? So he the story
is he goes into a store and he just
watches the clerk and he watches
customers with their credit card and
he's basically trying to figure out are
people going to stop taking American
Express because they no longer have
faith in the good standing of American
Express or is the American Express brand
going to with endure this? And really
the asymmetry was the market believed
that the that this would damage the
future of American Express uh and the
the quality of the brand. And what he
observed in watching people was that the
stores and the customers had no problem
using American Express and that there
was no there's no issue. And he did the
same thing. He does this very similar
thing with Apple where he had stayed
away from technology companies for a
long time. And then he realized like oh
when he talked to Apple customers he's
like not only would they not trade their
current device for a cheaper equivalent
of device by somebody else. You can't
pay these people to switch off Apple.
And it was the it was a more of a social
psychological observation, not a
technical or fundamental analysis of the
business that led him to to to invest in
those companies. So Chris, it's a
long-winded way of asking who else has
been great at this. What are the great
stories that inspire you on this or do
you feel like you're kind of the first
one to popularize this?
>> No, the concept of information asymmetry
is not new to investing methodologies.
The most famous person to adopt it
widely would have been Peter Lynch with
the Mellin fund in the 80s. The
difference is being a pure observational
social Arab investor is this concept
that it shouldn't be part of an
investing methodology but it should be
the only thing that you take into
consideration. Right? So Peter Lynch
kind of blended this this observational
investing approach. He would famously
walk the malls and kind of look at what
stores had the longest lines at the cash
register. See seems pretty simple,
right? And he would combine that with
massive amounts of fundamental research.
You have to ask yourself though
if the market is relatively efficient
and we know the market's never perfectly
efficient, but it's if it's relatively
efficient in terms of taking into
account
all the fundamentals and all the
technicals and you have all these
investors that are trying to price a
company based on all the known things.
Then if you're able to surface something
that's unknown
that is meaningful, you don't need to
worry about all the other stuff. You
don't need to have this robust
fundamental technical approach that also
happens to apply information asymmetry
when you come across it. You can focus
all of your energy and all of your
research on just finding
new information that the market hasn't
discovered yet and making an assumption
that [clears throat] the particular
company that you're trading is
relatively efficient with all the known
information and investors haven't fully
priced in this new piece of information.
So all you care about is that one piece
of information asymmetry. It simplifies
the way that investors can approach this
game because most of us are never going
to be technically proficient investors
and never going to be able to compete
with the absolute best most pedigreed
Wharton graduated like fundamental
investors, right? that are doing te deep
deep deep fundamental analysis and
they've come to terms with the fact that
this company should trade at a 29p as
opposed to the 24 PE it's trading at
today. I mean I don't want to play that
game. The easiest game to play because
you can invest a million different ways.
So the question is what is the best
approach to investing that the largest
chunk of ordinary people can actually
apply efficiently to markets and
regularly do that in a fruitful way. And
I strongly believe it's pure
observational social investing.
>> Sean, I actually just Googled this and
it's funny. I'm quoted as the source of
Google uh for this story. So, it could
be a little bit rock, but in 1966, a
young Warren Buffett visited a movie
theater on 45th and Broadway in New York
to watch Mary Poppins. He went with a
briefcase in the middle of the
afternoon, later joking that it almost
felt like he needed to rent a kid to fit
in. This trip was his way of researching
Disney to see if they had lasting brand
appeal. And later that day, he bought 5%
of the company at $4 million, and it was
a 50% gain over the next year. And he
says selling it, which he did after one
year, was one of his biggest mistakes
that he's ever made. And by the way, so
I if he really believed that that
lasting, durable brand appeal was there
for Disney, right? Did he also believe
that the the rest of the world came to
that acknowledgement after a year? And
if he did, then he didn't have any alpha
after a year. And he was probably right
to sell Disney. Um, and Disney
>> only 35 when he did that, by the way. So
I mean, you could also say maybe he just
made a mistake.
>> But you have to understand something.
Whether a stock goes up or down after
you sell might have nothing to do with
you making a mistake because that's not
your thesis. That's not why you
invested. You don't have any alpha. So
it could have gone up for a completely
different reason. So you got to get out
of the headsp space of saying because a
stock continued to go up after you
exited you made the mistake. You that
could be completely coincidental. It
went up for something that you had no
knowledge into that you had no take on.
How do you quantify that though? Because
like for example, Sean and I or the
average Joe might have like uh an
opinion on one company. Their sales we
think are going up, but that doesn't
necessarily mean the stock will change.
>> Okay, let's take a step back. If you are
correct that a company is being impacted
by something meaningfully and their
revenue is going to go up and the rest
of the investor class is not aware of
that yet.
If there's nothing else impacting that
company during that trade window, it is
highly likely again there are a lot of
factors. There's the macro market. the
market could come down right there. But
but in a vacuum,
that piece of information will almost
always in a vacuum will almost always
result in the stock going up. Because
when a company makes more money than the
market anticipates,
the stock will go up. If you're able to
surface something that will impact a
company's sales that the rest of the
market is not aware of when the rest of
the world comes to terms with that piece
of information that will positively
impact the stock price, assuming that
there's nothing else going on with that
company or the market at large, but I I
wouldn't overthink it. Too many
investors overthink this. It's not that
complicated. Guys,
>> can you give a sense of volume? Uh, so I
think you said something like 80 80
investment decisions 17 years. That does
that mean you're making fourish buy,
sell trade decisions per year, or did I
hear that wrong? Cuz my my my hunch was
that you're a little more active than
that? Seems like in a given year, how
how many decisions are how many
investment decisions are you making? So
I'm referring to high conviction trades,
you know, trades where I have a lot of
conviction and I'm generally
allocating
five to 30% of my total portfolio to
buying that stock or I'm allocating call
it 2 to 15% of my portfolio to buying
options in that stock. By the way, when
you say portfolio, is this like I have
my trading my fun my fun slush fund and
then I have my boring safe nest egg over
here.
>> Entire portfolio.
>> Entire portfolio. Yes.
>> I think what Sean was getting at was
like do you have like a safety net?
>> No. I mean on my my public equity
portfolio is my public equity portfolio.
It's just one portfolio. So when I have
high conviction in a trade, I will
allocate between like I said, I don't
know up to a third of my portfolio might
be in that single stock for that period
of time that I'm in that trade. And
Sean, to answer your question, uh in the
early years, I would average one to two
high conviction trades a year. Uh now as
we have more social media today than we
had back 13 years ago and the world is
more digitally connected today and
there's it's actually easier than it's
ever been to read into the world's
conversations as they're happening.
Like, as you guys know, I spend hours a
night reading comments on Tik Tok videos
because that's where most of the world
organically shares what they're doing,
what they're buying, you know, where
they're going, like on a daily basis.
I I've increased the velocity of my high
conviction trades. So, there have been
years now where I've had six or seven
high conviction trades in a year where
it used to be one or two,
>> right? And by the way, the the more
change that's happening in the world,
the more opportunity to surface a high
conviction trade. So probably the
biggest year I ever had was during the
pandemic because the year of the
pandemic there was a tremendous amount
of change happening in the world. We all
started living at home, you know,
working from home, right? We we we
stopped going out. We started buying
things that we would ordinarily never
buy. uh we stopped spending money on
those things and started spending money
on these things because we're living
inside of our house for a year straight.
You know, we're buying bicycles and
cameras for our computers and printers
cuz the kids are doing homeschooling and
all of these things. So, we're buying
Pelatons cuz we're not going to the gym
and we're working out at our house now.
So, you know, we're shopping more on
Amazon and Spotify. So like the more
change, the more opportunity for an
observational investor to surface that
change and connect the dots to
investable opportunities. When there's
not a lot of change in the world, then
there's less opportunity for us. So what
what I've been telling people is in the
age of AI, we've never experienced this
type of global change before other than
the pandemic because AI is radically
changing the way that we think about
work that we think about intelligence.
every company in the world is going to
get hit positively or negatively due to
the way that AI and and unlimited
intelligence is going to impact their
sector over the next few years. So, this
is an amazing time to be an
observational social investor because
the world is changing so quickly.
There's going to be so many winners and
losers.
So the game here is to figure out what's
changing and the degree to which that
change is good or bad for any given
company at any given period of time.
>> Does this influence you, Sean? Uh this
is your second time talking to him. Are
you uh has your actions changed since
December?
>> Uh not necessarily because the main
thing I do isn't like active investing
in in public equities. you know, if I
did, maybe uh it would be a little more,
but I don't know. I find it fascinating
and like you said, we talked to on one
end of the spectrum, you know, uh sort
of the Charlie Mer Buffett uh disciples.
We've had those value investors on,
we've had, um you know, Howard Marx,
he's dealing in in uh you know, debt and
bonds and and you know, you have Ray
Dalio, you have all these different
people. So, I'm more of a right now in a
kind of curiosity mode, not a, "Oh,
great. Let me switch up my style every
time I talk to a really successful,
really interesting investor, which for
us on this podcast is like every month."
>> You But let me ask you a question. Your
audience,
what what do you think the average
follower of this show looks like? Do you
think the average follower of this show
is capable of being a top 1%
fundamental
investor competing against literally
hundreds?
>> Well, I don't think that the average the
average listener of the show couldn't be
a top 1% in any type of investing.
>> That's completely untrue. That's
ridiculous. I think for
>> I don't think that's ridiculous to say
the average person can't be able
>> that that is that is patently false.
Patently false. Where do you think Where
do you think I graduated in my high
school class? Just just guess
percentise.
>> Either 1% or the worst percent. I'm not
sure where I should guess.
>> But no no genuin like genuinely I turn I
generated 80 million off a $20,000
portfolio. Like like I I I I am who I
am. you could, you know, look at the
last 15 years of stuff and articles like
genuinely like objectively
like where do you think I would have
graduated in my high school class of
public school?
>> Just back up. The question was the
average person of our show, are they a
1% investor? I don't think they are. Nor
do I think
>> Oh, no. I'm sorry. I didn't mean that. I
meant do they have the capacity?
>> Also, no.
>> Okay. Well, I'm I'm asking. So, like,
let's talk about if we talk about IQ,
like what do you think my IQ? I had an
IQ test. What do you think my IQ was? Or
what where do you think I graduated in
my high school class? Just just
objectively, just throw it out there.
>> Middle. Sean.
>> Well, you're asking the question, which
tells me it's got to be in the bottom
half of your class.
>> It's lower than that. It's uh bottom 25%
of my high school class. I barely
graduated. And uh I'll just tell you
this. I'm not I don't recall my exact
IQ, but I will tell you this. When I was
in kindergarten, okay, I was the only
kid in the class that didn't know what
my last name was, and they sent me to
Manhattan to get an IQ test. And I still
had that piece of paper. It was slightly
below average in terms of IQ. Nothing
crazy. They kept me in the class.
I don't know why I didn't know my last
name. Honestly, [laughter]
I'm just saying I didn't I was the only
kid that didn't know my last name. I
went on to do not a lot better through
my senior year of high school.
Obviously, I was bottom 25% of my class.
>> What about temperament? Because like you
again, we've talked to all these amazing
people. A huge takeaway that I've had
talking to a bunch of the investors in
particular is that temperament probably
matters more than IQ. And I think the
your temperament, the way you were born
is likely just the way it is. You
probably can't change it. I think Sean
talked to Manish Pbry and he said
something I think it was him Sean he
said something like I probably can't
take anyone and make them great but we
could probably improve you a little bit.
You know, I think he didn't say this,
but it was like the analogy of you're
born 7 feet tall. And you could be
better at basketball at 6' tall, but
like, you know, freaks are freaks. And
so, um, temperament, I actually think is
probably more important than IQ when it
comes to this game.
>> Okay. I would say that being a top 1%
observational investor, just a top 1%
investor generally,
is easily doable.
if you're willing to aggressively
adopt being an observational purist
investor. And the reason I say that is
because what I actually do is so simple
and so straightforward
and I've seen over the past seven or
eight years since I've been public about
this on YouTube and I have, you know,
hundreds of thousands of followers. I
have people around the world writing me
near daily. They are dentists. They are
janitors. They drive trucks for UPS.
They work in a parking lot checking out
cars. Okay? And they will DM me, hey
Chris, I've been watching you for 5
years. I started doing this. I was early
to this company or to this company based
on what I observed in the world. It's
that one investment
has changed my entire life. And and I
tell people if you have one or two home
runs over 20 years, one or two home runs
over 20 years, meaning you find
something early and you put a meaningful
amount of money in it, that could put
you into the one or 2% range of all
investors over over that two decade
period. And that's all it takes. And a
perfect example of that is Tesla. Okay,
I actually wasn't early into Tesla, but
do you know how many terrible investors
otherwise? I mean, these are people that
hadn't done anything in their entire
life in the investing world and probably
haven't done much since are 1% investors
because they were behind the wheel of a
Tesla in early days and they realized
this is a gamecher and they put some
meaningful not even that meaningful just
some reasonable amount of money into
Tesla stock and that one investment
made them a top 1% global investor for
like a 10 or 15 year period or 20-year
period and changed the trajectory of
their entire life. They're not hyper
intelligent. They're probably like any
regular person. They're probably like
most of the people that watch this show
or any other show. And it's all about
just understanding that that's all it
takes because most people never even try
this because they think I can't compete
with pedigreed investors from Wall
Street. I can't spend 6 hours a day
doing technical trading. They don't
realize you don't need to. You can just
go on with your life. Live your life.
Just keep your mind open to potentially
early discovering the next big thing.
That's it. That's literally it. Like
that's all you have to do. What are the
things you have most high conviction in
right now?
>> Um my highest conviction trade I'm like
a broken record on this. It sounds so
weird because it's not a small company.
It's Amazon, guys. Like I I have more
money in Amazon. This the most
concentrated position I've had in a
really long time. I always say the most
concentrated position I've ever taken
was Nintendo when they came out with the
Wii because I was at the E3 conference
and actually saw this is like a Buffett
story, right? I actually saw the line of
people interacting with the Nintendo Wii
for the first time. I don't know if you
remember that gamechanging platform and
nobody on Wall Street believed it.
Everyone on Wall Street was so
hyperfocused on the Xbox coming out and
the PlayStation coming out, nobody
thought the Wii was going to be a big
deal. I was there. I saw it in real
life. I had a 100% of my portfolio
invested in a Nintendo ADR, which is a
tracking stock that tracks the Japanese
ticker of Nintendo. And I had 100% of my
portfolio, I think, for a full year in
Nintendo until Wall Street finally
realized how big of a deal that was. Uh,
but Amazon,
I I I just think it's the company that
is best positioned in the world to
benefit from the upcoming AI efficiency
wave, which is once we actually start to
see meaningful productivity jumps from
the AI age. Uh, there's no company in
the world that's going to benefit more
from that than Amazon. I also think they
are the nucleus of AI infrastructure.
So, so sorry. What's the observation you
made here? I I like what I is this not
from the Tik Tok comments in this
situation? Is this
>> No, this is this is this is a kind of a
global cultural shift and it's it's a
big observation I've had for 3 years
which is based in part I don't know if
you guys ever read Nasim Taleb's book
black swan
>> uh but black swan theory essentially
says that our minds are not capable of
fully recognizing and appreciating
anomalies in the market or the world
that haven't happened before. I had this
thesis in early days AI that AI wouldn't
just be the next internet. It's not just
going to be the next mobile phone or
smartphone, but that it would be
meaningfully larger than anything we've
experienced in our lifetime.
And as a result of that, we would see
the biggest trades of our life happen um
as a direct result of AI. And even when
the information was right in front of
us, the market would not believe it
until it actually shows up in the
numbers because there's no precedent for
what we're seeing in AI. There's nothing
that has ever happened in our lifetime
before AI that we can compare to AI. Now
I might regret saying this in 10 years
but I don't think so. I think the
concept of intelligence becoming
infinite and free to the world is going
to be the biggest change we've ever seen
in humanity. So the reason why Amazon
went down and has not really gone up as
a company meaningfully over you know
recently right is because they have made
such an aggressive investment in AI $200
billion now it's like 200 it's more than
200 billion this last year uh capex
investment in AI in a sector that nobody
knows if it's going to pay off for them
or not. Does that mean like um like for
example the did your guys' Siri or
what's it called? Alexa did your Alexa
just change where like now she like
talks to you like my Alexa just changed
so now it like talks like chat GBT like
I can ask real questions.
>> I would say the biggest example is this
is it's this simple. Amazon is betting
the entire company on AI. End of story.
As is some of the other big tech
companies, right? They are leveraging
all of their profits. They're leveraging
their balance sheet. They are building
out massive in infrastructure unlike
they ever had in the history of the
company. They are making the biggest
capex investment of any company in the
world by a big margin in AI. And the
world is still unsure about how this is
going to play out. I'm not unsure. I'm
willing to bet it all. They they think
that the infrastructure layer of AI
which is Amazon. Okay. Because Amazon
understand this. They are a chip
company, right? Their tranium, their
chips alone, their tranium AI chips are
generating like $50 billion of revenue
this next year. They are the one of the
largest infrastructure data center
companies in the entire world. and their
AWS platform and everything that they've
constructed in cloud computing over the
past 15 plus years sits at the center of
this architecture uh infrastructure for
AI. Okay. On top of that, Amazon is the
third largest digital advertising
company in the world. Okay. So as AI
makes advertising meaningfully more
efficient and targeted and effective and
personal and rich for consumers.
Amazon is at the center of that wave.
Additionally, Amazon has spent 20 years
building out the world's largest
logistical infrastructure for the
delivery of physical product to humans.
an investment that no other company has
even come close to making.
That investment even moving the margin
needle a few points is a gamecher for
Amazon. So as we enter this new world of
intelligence and automation and
robotics, okay,
Amazon already has the infrastructure as
the world's largest e-commerce company,
the largest logistics company to benefit
massively from the increases in
productivity and efficiencies that
infinite free intelligence. And
eventually what we're going to see is is
embodied intelligence, right, with
robotics, right? This is going to result
in productivity and efficiency gains
unlike we've ever experienced as humans.
And Amazon is the number one company to
benefit from all of that.
>> Sound like you're giving a sermon.
You're bought in.
>> And by the way, they own like 15% of
Anthropic, too.
>> They just And that's what's so funny
here. Now, if Anthropic IPOs between 1
and 2 trillion, which who knows? I think
there's a reasonable chance they will
next year, Amazon will make more money
off that IPO than the 200 billion they
spent on capex that everybody's so
worried about, right? And so, again, we
are living in an age when the market has
more noise than it's ever had. The
stories are changing every day. Like,
it's impossible as an investor to cut
through the noise. So that's what's so
difficult is is I think most new
investors, they just give up because
they're like, I can't keep up with all
this stuff. You don't have to keep up
with any of it. Just find one company
that kind of sits in a place where they
stand to benefit meaningfully from
something that you're seeing in the
world. It could be AI with Amazon. It
could be the fact, you know, one of my
big trades recent, you know, one of my
big trade thesises recently is
flip-flops are trending this summer,
right? Because last summer there were
$750 flip flops made by a company called
Row and now every person in the world
wants to wear flip flops because they're
they're on trend. You can go out at
night to a club wearing flip flops. And
so there's a Brazilian company uh that
is one of the largest, you know, makers
of flip-flops.
There's so many ways
um to to kind of like arb change in the
world. When you you said Amazon was your
most concentrated bet in a long time,
what does that mean percentage-wise for
you?
>> Amazon
right now is about
50% of my portfolio
value. On top of that,
>> did you say 50 or 15?
>> 50.
On top of that, I have options in Amazon
that account for, you know, another 50%.
So theoretically, I mean, yeah, if you
count the the the amount that those
options represent, it could be like 70%
of my portfolio is Amazon right now.
That's how confident I am in a trade. So
after you make a bet like that, you
know, um Ed Thorp has this cool book,
you know, the famous uh investor, one of
the early hedge fun guys where he kind
of like a funny stories. He's like, I
make my trade and then I just go and
hang out for like 6 months and I just
see what happens. And there's like
stories of him like playing tennis
throughout the day and they're like,
"Shouldn't you be at work?" He's like,
"I made the trade. Let's see what's
going to happen." So are you making that
bet and then kind of stepping away for a
little while or are you going to be are
you active every single day then? I love
that concept. By the way, I've been
saying for months, this is the summer to
deep research your trade. Make it and
then just walk away because 99% of the
noise hitting this market on a
day-to-day basis, week-toeek basis,
doesn't matter at all. And there is not
that much happening and changing
where you need to be that concerned
about the market on a day in and day day
out basis. Now, I'm not completely just
going off and playing tennis for the
rest of the summer. I I'm keeping up
with what's happening in the market, but
I don't think there's going to be
anything that's going to happen over the
course of the next few weeks to couple
months that would meaningfully change my
thesis on Amazon. something might. Uh,
but my thesis on Amazon is fairly large
and it's it it it's based on something
that I believe is going to unravel over
the next few years as opposed to unravel
over the next few months. So, it it it's
a massive concentration risk that I'm
putting on this trade. But this this is
what I do, right? Like you you can't
generate outsiz returns without taking
outside risk. You just can't do it. By
the way, guys, I don't think that most
people should be doing this across their
entire portfolio. I always tell people
like, and I'm not a financial adviser,
obviously, but you got to bucket
your assets for different risk
categories, right? So, I think everybody
should have a big money account. I don't
care if you start with $50 in that
account, but everyone should have an
account where they're willing to take
big risk for big gains. And you don't
have to take your kids, you know,
college savings to put in that account
or your retirement money in that
account. You could just start making
tradeoffs in your life. Like, I don't
know, mow your own lawn or make your own
coffee. But every dollar that you save,
put it in this big money account and
then use it to actually take a big risk
every once in a while in something that
you believe in so that you have a chance
of becoming a top 1% investor, but do it
with tradeoffs. Do it with other
people's money, right? Like get your
haircut every 5 weeks instead of every
four weeks. I don't know. like delay
that big purchase 6 months so the big
screen TV is $200 less than it was 6
months earlier. Take the $200 you saved.
Put it in your big money investment
account. If that's how you fund that
account, then you're not a afraid to
take a concentrated risk. If you're
co-mingling your money altogether, it
could be really hard to take a big risk
on something because it's
psychologically difficult for you to
throw that much money into a risky
investment. So, you have to bucket your
money. This is like one of the most
important lessons for investors.
I'm willing to do it, right? Like I'm If
Amazon is the stock that takes me down
as an investor and ruins my reputation,
then let it be. Well, it's definitely
not going to take you It won't take you
down. Uh Well, I don't know. Well, I
don't know how leveraged you are, but I
mean, it's not like it's like a It's not
like it's it's not going to it ain't
going away.
>> No, it Well, well, you never know. It It
could. But here's the thing, guys. I
have been so transparent about
everything I've ever done in the market.
I talk about everything. I talk about
the good, the bad, the risk factors. Um,
and when I lose, I talk about how much
money I lost. I I I do not advise anyone
to try to mirror my trades. I just want
people to see how I think. I want them
to see how I think about risk, how I
think about uh concentration, how I
think about,
you know, observational investing. I
just share everything with the world.
And by the way, you guys, I think, know
this. I'm one of the only I don't I'm
sure there's at least a couple others
financial content creators. I've never
sold anything. I don't have courses. I
don't sell a thing. What's is your
community free?
>> Dude, I don't even take sponsorships. Do
you know that I haven't taken one
sponsorship my entire life? I won't take
$1 from an advertiser. I won't take $1
from a community member. Not what the
only thing that's ever been sold is we
sell some t-shirts and hoodies at cost.
You know, I take that back. You know,
the value I get out of my community is
collaboration. I I get so many great
ideas from our community and they help
vet my own ideas. That's probably made
me more money than I could have ever
have made from courses and selling
sponsorships and all that stuff.
>> By the way, I have a lot a lot of
respect for that. I think uh you know, a
I trust that uh my trust goes up. Like I
said, I was very skeptical of finance
and stock influencers and traders on on
YouTube, but you know, the fact that
you're not selling courses, not charging
for community, not taking sponsors and
all that, that that is, I think,
extremely commendable and extremely
rare. So, I got to give you props for
that. to be to be on I mean here's the
deal like we always say it like if
you're so great at something which that
come on I mean been I've been great the
last 17 years I make an insane amount of
money from my portfolio like I don't
need to do any of that like like I the
amount of money I make is public right
so I don't I'm very fortunate to not
have to do that and I just don't need to
do that so I don't want to do that but I
do have an overriding goal here my goal
My mission in life is to bring every
human on earth into the investor class.
And that's why I'm on YouTube. That's
why I'm on X. That's why I talk. That's
why I do shows like this. I And I truly
believe that this style of investing,
it's something that you could do for
fun. You could do it on the side. You
don't have to quit your job. You just
retrain your brain to start thinking
about this stuff. And you might only get
one great investment the next 10 years,
but that one investment, if you have a
big money account, and if and when you
find it, whether it's the next Tesla or
the next whatever, you're willing to
throw a lot of money behind it, that
could be the thing that changes your
entire life. Um, and my next big thesis
is
podcasters, which sounds insane because
there's so many podcasters, right? Like,
you got to be kidding, Chris. Don't we
have too many podcasters?
Let me just say this. In the age of AI
that we're about to enter into,
we are going to deeply appreciate
humans. I think that's my thesis. And
while we will embrace technology and AI
and efficiencies and all the wonderful
things it's going to bring to us, I
think we will equally appreciate the
most human voices and human
personalities.
And we are going to need that for
connectivity to remind us of what's
real.
>> So what's the bet like? What would the
product be? The bet is that we are just
getting started with podcasting and I
believe the entirety of the future of
media is new media and podcasters
will continue to get bigger and bigger.
I think the most human of human voices
will become infinitely valuable the next
10 years. I think within the podcasting
sector, I think women are slow to become
podcasters because we have so many
brilliant solo creators that are women
on TikTok, but women tend to be really
intimidated by friction, by bridging
into podcasting when you need to have
camera equipment and editors and
clippers and you need to have staff,
right? It's and you need to invest money
and capital. So, I believe the most
talented women voices in the world are
not yet podcasting.
So, I'm opening up a podcast incubation
studio in Austin, Texas, where we are
going to attempt to develop a very
boutique studio, but we're going to
attempt to identify the most talented
women voices in the world that are
currently doing content as solo creators
and help them bridge into the world of
durable, repeatable podcasting, which we
believe is just getting started. I think
if you move forward 5 to 8 years, there
will be hundreds of podcasts that are
worth $100 million or more. I'm not
doing this for the money. I'm doing this
because I I just I know that this could
be really big. And I have so much fun
working with other creative people. I
love podcasters generally. I it's all I
do is watch podcasts, right? And and and
sit in on podcasts. But when I look at
like women's podcasting, you know, 70%
of podcasters are men. So I think
there's this huge opportunity the next
few years as podcasting becomes more
programmatic
uh to help develop podcast into what
they will be cuz I don't think the
future of podcasting is like two people
in a studio talking on mics. No offense.
I [laughter] mean I mean my my my show
is three guys in a studio talking on
mics. I I I think it will become uh I
think it will be that probably for
financial podcasters and and and
business podcast but I think for like
general audience podcast
especially for women it will become more
programmatic.
>> When you when you say programmatic what
does that mean? Okay. So, are you
familiar with uh Financial Audit Caleb
Hammer's show out of Austin? He's he's
the third biggest podcast in the world
on YouTube.
>> Okay.
>> His show is program. He has an actual
program that expresses itself through a
podcast format. Okay. So, he has guests
on the show, but he has a very formal
program of entertainment, right?
And so that is the future of podcasting.
So we have to get more creative with
podcasting. We have to take risk. Caleb
took a big risk with what he did.
>> Have you seen Friends Keep Secrets?
>> No. What is that?
>> You got to check this. You're going to
love this. Uh so this is Lil Dicky the
rapper. Benny Blanco the producer.
>> Yeah. I'm sorry. I have seen it. It's
the greatest show ever. Yes.
>> To me that's an example of what you're
talking about. When I saw that, I was
like a little bit mind blown. And you
know, I'm doing podcasting twice a week
for 6 years. And what they came in and
did. I I really feel like the real
creatives have arrived into podcasting
cuz now you see Conan O'Brien's got a
podcast and hus got a podcast. Like the
real comedians have podcasts, the real
creatives have podcasts. And now what
they're doing to the format because they
come from a different background is
they're approaching it differently. like
they got a house and they stage the
cameras and the guest shows up almost
like a sitcom, you know, at the door and
then they open the door and then and
then they move from the kitchen to the
living room and they have these bits
that they do and the the way they do
their ad reads, you're like, "Ah, God,
their ad read is more entertaining than
my my actual content. Jesus, how I need
to I need to up my game." Sean Sean, you
you got it. You just you just nailed it.
Now fortunately again like the type of
podcasting that we do is kind of like
you know like education and business and
finance. I think we can afford to be
very slow to change because it's just
different for us. I think a lot of the
people that watch your show that watch
my show they primarily are looking to
get take something away from that show
in terms of education and growth and
learning. I think the personality
entertainment piece is like 10 to 20% of
the show. If if we tried to make it 50%,
we might lose our audience, right? But
um for the future of podcasting, I think
it looks very different
broaderbased. I think it's going to be
exciting. And like here's the thing,
guys. Like I've been talking about
stocks for 10 years. Like I love it, but
I kind of like I'm bored by it. So, like
I like diving into these different areas
where I get to be a bit more creative
with other,
>> you know, other creatives, uh, and not
just talk about stock. That's why I
enjoyed the Pokemon thing. Like, I
didn't collect Pokemon, but it was kind
of fun being around other people that
were passionate
>> about something. And like, in my mind,
I'm like, how do I make money off this,
guys? Like, how do I make money off of
Pokemon? That's how I did it. I I did it
from starting the convention that the
Pokemon enthusiast would come to and
enjoy. Right.
>> And you got to be the uncle and not the
father, right? Somebody else ran it and
you got to pitch in where it was helpful
and fun, but not necessarily the
dayto-day. Is that is that right?
>> I didn't I didn't have to do the full
dayto-day. I got to kind of do the
day-to-day when we would have shows, but
behind the scenes I wasn't working
full-time.
>> Yeah,
>> for sure. Um, but man, was it a
lucrative journey and damn was it fun.
It was so fun.
>> Thanks for doing this. You're uh now I'm
like I have all these notes like all
these rabbit holes I'm going to go down
this this uh the podcast thing, the the
collecton. That's crazy. You uh you got
layers. Well, you know what, guys? Like
here's the thing. I'm really fortunate
that I have this insane network of
people that I'm constantly meeting with.
A lot of them are hyper successful, you
know, billionaires in the back half of
their career or life. And I'm at a point
like, okay, if you've had success and
you can kind of do anything you want,
like what would it actually be? And and
I feel that for so many people in my
network, it always comes down to having
a bigger number. And I'm like, are you
sure that you're making decisions driven
by the right motivations? Because is
that bigger number actually going to
give you fulfillment in the way that you
think it is? And over the last couple of
years, I've come to the conclusion that
a bigger number for me is going to make
no difference in my level of contentment
or fulfillment in life. And I like the
concept of grinding and creating and
building and taking risk, but not if
it's to like get a bigger number. So
like if I'm going to do something the
next 3 to 5 years, whatever my next
thing is, like I want the journey to be
as fun as the outcome. So okay, my
outcome that I want is to land the top
20 global podcasts by developing two or
three shows over the next few years with
people I believe are unbelievably
talented. I want to build a great team
around them. I want to like I want to
it's the gamemanship of like can I do
this? There's tens of millions of
podcasts. How can if I landed a top 20,
how wild would that be? How? But I want
the journey in trying to figure out how
to win, how to get there to be fun. And
I know I love working with creative
people. I kind of because I've been
stuck in podcast world for the last
seven years. I kind of get it, right? So
like I and I love it. So like whether I
end up winning or losing and by the way,
if I win, I'm looking at I'm looking at
adding to my charitable foundation. And
that's like my number is not for me.
It's for it's for the foundation. But
the journey and how we get there will be
fun regardless. Like cuz I'm going to be
around creative people. I'm going to be
in a sector that I love. I mean when in
history could you take a few million
dollars and start a media company which
is exactly what I'm doing right now.
Like could you imagine like 20 years ago
you couldn't do that. You just couldn't
do that. Right now you can you can land
the top five show globally if you if you
execute in 3 years, two years, right?
Like isn't that wild that like you could
do that out of one studio with like 10
people, 10 or 15 people. Like how
exciting is that that you could play in
this game and you could have a top five
global global media show in a couple
years if you can find the right person
and the right team and the right format.
To me that that journey of just
attempting to accomplish that is maybe
the funnest thing I will ever do in my
life. So I'm really looking forward to
this next thing that I'm doing.
Hopefully we win, but even if we don't
win it, damn guys, I'm at a point I'm
going to have fun. I'm going to have fun
trying. [laughter] Okay.
And but and by the way, like I tell this
story to a guy. I had I had I had lunch
with a guy, massive exit. This I don't
know how much he's worth, but it's a
lot. And and I I talked to him about
this story and he said, "You know what,
Chris? I'm going to buy this bonsai shop
that me and my daughter go to." He goes,
"Cuz it's my favorite thing in the
world. Me and her go there and we just
hang out there and I'm going to buy it
and like this guy's going to end up
spending more time with his daughter.
He's going to have fun because he's
going to take this little bonsai shop
that's been around for 35 years and try
to grow it with her, which is kind of
cool. He's going to actually he he's an
AI guy, right? So like he's going to
actually like apply artificial
intelligence into the growth strategy
for the bonsai shop. He's going to maybe
get some content creators and
influencers to try to like take it
global through ecom. Like there's all
kinds of fun stuff you can do here.
Starting with a little bonsai store that
you and your daughter love. I'm like now
that's a great way to spend the next 5
years of your life. There's a lot of
people that have made it that have
enough money that they kind of can do
what they want. Like we're so set on
just like bigger number, more happy,
bigger. No, no, no, no. I actually
believe that there is a point when the
bigger number has the opposite effect.
It definitely 100% makes you less
fulfilled and less happy. Well, well,
you know why? Mo most people think
that's like a mo money, mo problems
thing, but it's it I I think underneath
that is you have no excuse left. you
know, for basically for when you don't
have a lot, you can always tell
yourself, well, it's on the other side
of this. And then once you get to once
you get there, there's nothing left to
blame for any lack any any internal
holes, any internal anxieties or um
feeling of lack um or just
dissatisfaction. And so, you can't you
can't blame that anymore. You've lost
the excuse. And I think that is a very
like tough moment for for people when
you don't you no longer can say well
it's because I don't have that that's
why I feel this way. It's like no no I
feel that way because that's how I am.
And that I think that's a pretty brutal
realization. At least that's what I've
felt and what I've seen that part of it.
I think a big part of it is that you
become disconnected with other humans
and you can't relate anymore and people
treat you differently and it gets harder
to maintain and develop authentic real
relationships. You can't do anything
about this. When you become excessively
wealthy to the point where nothing
matters anymore, you just don't relate
to daily things the same way as the rest
of your family and friends and
colleagues do and they sense that. And
then also when you meet new people and
like you like listen you start going to
certain types of vacations and certain
types of dinners and you hang out maybe
you have a yacht and maybe you fly
private and then it's like well this is
what I want to do with my time but I
just want to spend time with my friends.
So maybe your friends are now on your
yacht and doing $5,000 dinners and your
friends or maybe you have to bring them
on your private jet and like you're
paying for them and it makes things
really weird cuz then it's like wait a
second are these people they don't even
rip on me anymore. They don't even treat
me the same anymore. Maybe because
they're worried that like they're not
going to be part of this lifestyle that
I'm paying for only because they can't
be here unless I pay for it. And I don't
want to I want to live the lifestyle and
I want my friends to be with me. There's
just so many problems that organically
surface when you enter that stratosphere
which used to be like this many people
but in 2026 guys there are a lot of
people with excessive wealth. Let's be
honest, like the number of people that
have excessive wealth in 2026 for a
variety of reasons, okay,
are are enormous. The number of people
that fly private, the number of people
that spend $3,000, $2,000 a night on
hotel rooms and resorts, the number of
people that are going out to dinners at
these places where they're spending just
wilds amount of money on a regular
basis, the wealth class is huge. And I
think that ultra high netw worth wealth
class is probably miserable because of
all these factors. And it's really hard
to stay grounded.
[clears throat] It's exceptionally
difficult to like stay connected. And
you guys know there's nothing more
important in life than being deeply
connected with other humans. Nothing.
And this thing makes it very hard to
stay deeply connected. So, it's almost
like a hack not letting yourself get to
that point. Like, I know it sounds
crazy. There is there is a sweet spot. I
think there is a sweet spot for wealth
and it's different for every person and
you can kind of sense when you kind of
get out of the range of that sweet spot
cuz you can kind of sense these things
starting to happen. And there are a lot
of ways to knock yourself back down. One
of them is starting a foundation and
just giving money into the foundation,
right? It's not yours anymore. It's in
the It's not yours. You give the
foundation. It belongs to the foundation
and you get to do good things with it.
>> Also, you can take that money and like
you can invest it in other things that
puts it at risk. But again, it's not
yours when it's invested and illquid and
put at risk. So now your access to like
liquidity and your access to money that
you know is bankable becomes more
reasonable. and like you you don't push
yourself to into that stratosphere of
overspending on a regular basis.
>> I agree with every word you just said.
Every word you just said I I totally
agree with.
>> So I but I think it's a topic that quite
honestly not only people don't talk
about but I think most people don't even
think about because like your brain
doesn't My brain for some reason
>> well like if you don't do it
appropriately it sounds kind of douchy
if you talk about this stuff publicly. I
mean that's like the easy like but that
doesn't mean it shouldn't it's not an
important I mean like it's super helpful
it's just helpful to like maybe a small
group of people
>> there was a great blog post on this by
um Julie I think Zho was her name she
wrote a thing to all the folks who are
about to get rich it was right before
the SpaceX IPO and she was at Facebook
right before Facebook had its IPO and
she talked about what she observed and
saw of the people who you know had been
working really hard for a long time and
suddenly the sort of shackles of
liquidity were were off them and and now
they had the money and what what did you
do? And she talked about how people play
that game. And and Chris, your your
point on disconnection is one that she
made. I'll read you a little part of it.
She's she's like, um, once money can buy
you anything, you become a bit bit of a
character. You can eat at fancy
restaurants all the time. You bring a
full zoo and carnival and a chocolate
train to your kids three-year-old
birthday party. You know, you become so
cloaked by these fancy things, shiny
things that you can you can buy. And
that sparkling cloak can become so
distracting that people can no longer
see you. You become harder to connect
with. and she talks about like the it's
the the disconnection can lead to is is
a great source of unhappiness. You know,
I saw this with a I have a friend who
got very very wealthy through real
estate, bought a mega mansion,
18,000 square ft. He's literally not
only did he move away from his friends
and family because we don't afford to
live in that place that that
neighborhood that neighborhood has acres
in between houses. Um but then even in
his own house he was disconnected from
his own kids were you know on the in the
west wing and he's on the east wing
10,000 feet apart the money literally I
watched it make him less happy um
because it would created an immense
amount of social disconnection on on
many many levels and I I remember when I
first moved to San Francisco I worked
with this guy he's a billionaire and we
went out to lunch um as a group of us
five of us and uh at the end he was like
you know he tossed his card in but he
was he basically was like oh should we
all just put our cards in And I was
like, man, this guy, what a cheap
billionaire. This guy didn't even pick
up the tab. And I realized like actually
it wasn't because he's cheap at all.
He's not a cheap guy at all. He's very
generous. But he didn't want to change
the social dynamic between us where it
became this weird power dynamic or this
weird like subservient thing. And he was
actually doing us all quite a big favor
by not doing that. So you start to see
these little moments of possible
disconnection versus connection.
>> Facts. I I always wondered like why am I
seeing this and none of the other people
or very few that are in the same place
seem to see it. I think it's because
I've like retrained my mind to be an
observational investor. So I'm
constantly observing life and culture
and rel like everything I'm just being
hyper observant about and it kind of
translated to this and I was hyper
observant about this the part the
birthday like all this stuff right and I
was like damn I cannot fall into that
trap. I do not want to be miserable.
Like a lot of the people that I see and
you know you've seen this, right? Like
they fall into the traps and then it's
like it never leads to a good place.
>> But I will say this also cuz a lot of
people will see shows like this and like
oh it's so easy for you guys to talk
about you know this when you have it. I
will admittedly the sweet spot is pretty
sweet. Okay. So like so I'm just going
to say the sweet spot of wealth is
pretty sweet. So, do don't
mischaracterize what we're talking
about.
Gaining financial independence is one of
the most amazing things one could ever
experience in life. What that buys you
is actually insane. Being in full
control over your time, how you spend
it, who you're with, where you go, and
never having to work for someone else
again. That is magical. that actually is
as good as you think it is. It really
is. It's actually better. It's be it's
better. Okay. It's I remind I talked to
some of my friends. I'm like, "Hey, um
dude, I just like a reminder, dude. We
hadn't worked a real job in like 15
years." Like, that's pretty freaking
nuts. Like, and my buddies are like,
"Yeah, dude. We forget how good we have
it." I'm like I'm like, "Do you know
like how many of our friends and
colleagues are still getting up every
day and going to the job we had 15 years
ago?" And because we became independent
investors and became part of the
investor class and aggressively invested
money in equity markets and now we're
independently financially free. We're
podcasters and we're investing and we're
working really hard. We're starting
businesses and backing other businesses.
We're probably working harder than we've
ever worked in life. But it's optional.
It's optional and we're doing it because
we enjoy it and we're financially free
to be at every kid soccer game. We're
financially free to be with our family
and our friends whenever we want,
however we want. Like I used to have the
cubicle job for many, many years, guys.
Many, many, many years. I had the job in
the cubicle uh doing sales calls, right?
And so I try to never forget how awesome
it is to like not be in that position.
So yeah, I I don't mean to rip on
getting wealthy because it's pretty damn
awesome. It's just [laughter]
keep it manageable cuz there is a point
of diminishing returns and then there's
a point of deeply deeply negative
returns on every dollar you spend. Not
every dollar you make, but every dollar
you spend after after that point.
>> You're cool, man.
>> Chris, this was fun. I like having uh we
like having you on. We like talking to
you. You got to do a part three now.
>> Dude, you guys are you guys are the
best. I would I'm always up for it. I I
love it.
>> Well, we appreciate you so much.
>> That's it. That's the pod.